<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rose Porta</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rose Porta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal Crossing</title>
      <link>/2020/05/07/animal-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/07/animal-crossing/</guid>
      <description>Animal Crossing is a Nintendo video game, and the latest version, Animal Crossing New Horizons, released on March 20th 2020 is the latest trend among gamers. It is an open-ended simulation game where the goal is to create a community of anthropomorphic animals on a deserted island. If you want to learn more about it, the wikipedia page is here 1.
The #TidyTuesday data this week contains information about Animal Crossing reviews by both critics and consumers 2 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDPR Violations</title>
      <link>/2020/05/03/gdpr-violations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/03/gdpr-violations/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for the summer is to practice my R skills using data provided by the R for Data Science Tidy Tuesday Project 1. A data set is posted on the Tidy Tuesday github repository every week, and the goal is to wrangle and vizualize the data and share your plots on twitter using #TidyTuesday. I was inspired by Smith College Alumna Sara A. Stoudt (@sastoudt on twitter), who is currently persuing a Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description> My name is Rose Porta and I am a current student at Smith College class of 2023. I plan to major in Statisitical and Data Sciences and minor in Dance.
Contact Info email: rporta@smith.edu
twitter: @porta_rose
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Spring 2020 Multiple Regression Final Project: Analysis of Sleep and Anxiety as Predictors of BMI Final Report
Github Repository
  Fall 2019 SDS 192 Final Project: Does holding kids back increase their odds of academic success? https://eager-mcclintock-33c6b1.netlify.app/
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>