<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rose Porta</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rose Porta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Ratings</title>
      <link>/2020/07/08/coffee-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/08/coffee-ratings/</guid>
      <description>1
This week’s #TidyTuesday data contains information about the professional ratings (on a 0-100 scale) of many varieties of coffee from around the world 2 3. The overall score for each variety is recorded along with sub-scores specifically rating various qualities of the coffee including aroma, flavor, aftertaste, acidity, body, balance, uniformity, sweetness, and moisture (1-10 scale). The species of the coffee, either Arabica or Robusta, is also recorded. This week, instead of using visualizations, I have taken a slightly different approach to this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claremont Run of X-Men</title>
      <link>/2020/07/01/claremont-run-of-x-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/01/claremont-run-of-x-men/</guid>
      <description>1
Uncanny X-Men is a comic book series by Chris Claremont that was extremely popular between 1975 and 1991. Several versions of X-Men comic books have been published with the first series having been launched in 1963, and yet the version titled ‘Uncanny X-Men’ was the longest run of any mainstream superhero writer on one title 2 3. The plot is based on a team of mutant superheros who gained their superpowers by having been born with an “X-Gene” 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caribou Locations</title>
      <link>/2020/06/24/caribou-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/24/caribou-locations/</guid>
      <description>1
The woodland caribou is a North-American subspecies of reindeer that is classified as “Vulnerable” on the International Union for the Conservation of Nature’s (IUCN) Red List as a result of the drastic decreases in population over the past few years 2 3. According to the report from a BC Ministry of Environment study, this population decline can be mainly attributed to increased predation of caribou by grey wolves at least partly resulting from disruption of habitat by human activities 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African-American History</title>
      <link>/2020/06/16/african-american-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/16/african-american-history/</guid>
      <description>1
Background and Purpose In honor of the week of Juneteenth, this week’s #TidyTuesday data contains information about the history of African-American slavery 2. Juneteenth (June 19th) is a holiday commemorating the day that a small subset of enslaved people in Texas, one of the last groups to hear the news, heard that they had been freed by the Emancipation Proclamation. Although freedom came little by little to different regions of the nation at different times and was not official until the 13th amendment was passed in December of 1965, the local blacks of the area in Texas decided on June 19th as their day of celebration, and the holiday gradually came to be recognized across the country 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African American Achievements</title>
      <link>/2020/06/08/african-american-achievements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/08/african-american-achievements/</guid>
      <description>In support of Black Lives Matter, this week’s #TidyTuesday data highlights African American pioneers in many areas including entertainment, science, politics, military, sports, religion, law, and more between 1738 and 2019 1. For each achievement, the data contains a summary of the achievement, the individual’s name, the year of the achievement, the gender of the individual, and the broad category the achievement falls under. For a full list of the achievements, see this wikipedia article 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marble Races</title>
      <link>/2020/06/01/marble-races/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/01/marble-races/</guid>
      <description>1
Marble racing has become a recent trend. It involves dropping marbles into a track, and the marble that stays in the track the longest wins. When the marble goes into the track, it swirls around a structure shaped like a funnel, and then eventually drops through the hole of the funnel into another funnel and repeats the process through a series of funnels until it falls all the way out of the track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocktails</title>
      <link>/2020/05/25/cocktails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/25/cocktails/</guid>
      <description>1
Creating cocktails is a delicate art. This week’s #TidyTuesday data contains recipe information for many different types of cocktails including the ingredients and amounts of each ingredient in each drink 2 3.
I used this data to examine the top 5 ingredients by frequency (how many different recipes the ingredient appears in) and amount (total volume of ingredient in ounces across all recipes) for each of 8 different categories of cocktails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beach Volleyball</title>
      <link>/2020/05/18/beach-volleyball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/18/beach-volleyball/</guid>
      <description>1
Beach volleyball is a team sport very similar to indoor volleyball, except it is normally played on the beach. The goal is to hit the ball over the net and onto the ground on the other team’s side of the net. Both men and women can play beach volleyball at a professional level.
This week’s #TidyTuesday data contains information about the winning and losing team’s players and plays for matches played in the The FIVB Beach Volleyball World Tour (international) and for tours organized by the Association of Volleyball Professionals (AVP, U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volcano Eruptions</title>
      <link>/2020/05/13/volcano-erruptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/13/volcano-erruptions/</guid>
      <description>1
Volcanic eruptions are incredible geological phenomena, but they can also cause significant damage to the environment and surrounding populations. According to wikipedia, a volcanic eruption occurs when a crack in Earth’s crust allows hot lava, volcanic ash, and gases to escape from below the surface 2.
This week the #TidyTuesday data includes information about volcanic eruptions over time including the names of the volcanos, the dates of all eruptions between 11345 B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal Crossing</title>
      <link>/2020/05/07/animal-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/07/animal-crossing/</guid>
      <description>Animal Crossing is a Nintendo video game, and the latest version, Animal Crossing New Horizons, released on March 20th 2020 is the latest trend among gamers. It is an open-ended simulation game where the goal is to create a community of anthropomorphic animals on a deserted island. If you want to learn more about it, the wikipedia page is here 1.
The #TidyTuesday data this week contains information about Animal Crossing reviews by both critics and consumers 2 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDPR Violations</title>
      <link>/2020/05/03/gdpr-violations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/03/gdpr-violations/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for the summer is to practice my R skills using data provided by the R for Data Science Tidy Tuesday Project 1. A data set is posted on the Tidy Tuesday github repository every week, and the goal is to wrangle and vizualize the data and share your plots on twitter using #TidyTuesday. I was inspired by Smith College Alumna Sara A. Stoudt (@sastoudt on twitter), who is currently persuing a Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>